<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-25T12:47:25+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Beautiful House agency</title><subtitle>Beautiful House agency offers ELEGANT CREATIVE solutions to bespoke requirements, using systematic methodology with HIGH-DEFINITION PRECISION.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Cottage Charm</title><link href="/2018/02/10/third-post-for-testing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cottage Charm" /><published>2018-02-10T18:23:03+02:00</published><updated>2018-02-10T18:23:03+02:00</updated><id>/2018/02/10/third-post-for-testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/02/10/third-post-for-testing.html">&lt;h2&gt;A couple revives a century-old compound perched above Maryland’s Severn Rive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baltimore residents knew they were onto something sublime when they built a weekend getaway on a bluff overlooking the Severn River near Annapolis more than 100 years ago. The simple cottage was perched high enough to enjoy dramatic views, yet situated only a stone’s throw down to the shore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, multiple owners altered and expanded the home and its outbuildings; a stable evolved into a guest house and a brick carriage house into a garage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the current owners spotted the property for sale online, they also knew they’d found a gem. The retired Navy officer and his wife, then living in a San Diego high-rise, wanted to move back to their old stomping grounds near Annapolis. “I went to the Naval Academy and my wife went to Towson, so we’re both attracted to the area,” says the husband. “We wanted to be on the Severn and we wanted a family compound that would attract our three grown kids and grandkids for visits.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After seeing the property in person, the couple purchased it and moved East to begin a new chapter in this pristine setting. “It’s the bluff that gets you,” says the homeowner. “You look out over a widening in the river—it’s almost like a private lake right there. That’s what won us over.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing their minimal apartment furniture would be lost in the three-bedroom main home, the owners hired designer Gina Fitzsimmons to furnish the interiors in a casual coastal style. “The first time I walked the property, I fell in love with it,” says Fitzsimmons. “It’s so charming; it has a Nantucket feeling.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The designer set out to create a “cottagey” look, employing a neutral palette enlivened with waves of blue. She freshened up the kitchen, installing a new backsplash. And in the adjacent breakfast/sitting room, she replaced a Victorian fireplace with a new one surrounded by crisp paneling aligned with the windows above. Subtle cues, from driftwood sconces to a Sam Moore chair with a “porthole” back, pay homage to the shore. “I used a lot of bold, nautical-looking stripes without going overboard,” Fitzsimmons explains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She created a tranquil refuge in the sunroom overlooking the river. Rattan chairs and sisal rugs lend an organic note. And Fitzsimmons expertly scaled the furniture to fit the more formal living and dining rooms. For example, a pair of petite loveseats in the living room leaves plenty of space for the couple’s baby grand piano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the main home was complete, the owners set their sights on upgrading the run-down guest house. For help, they called on local architect Scott Rand, who renovated the main house in 1996 for the previous owners. When Rand and builder Pat Mona inspected the former stable, they uncovered how rudimentary its construction was. “There was very little in the way of foundation and it was just not salvageable,” the homeowner recalls. “So we essentially tore it down and Scott designed a new guest house in the same footprint.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rand fashioned the two-bedroom, one-and-a-half-bath structure to mimic the lines of the main cottage. “I used the same windows and trim and the same roof pitches,” says the architect. “There’s a commonality.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the dust settled in the guest house, Fitzsimmons returned to work her magic on its interiors, creating inviting spaces that echo her work in the main home. “I tried to use similar elements, but introduced teal instead of blue to give it a different twist,” she recounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winding brick-and-stone pathways swathed in greenery and hydrangea lead to a terrace overlooking the water. Rustic stairs made of concrete and oyster shells descend to the Severn, where the owners are building a new sea wall that will contain a sandy area for their grandchildren to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire property has become a true family refuge. “There is the waterfront for sports, Annapolis is a great town and having Washington, DC, close by also makes it an attraction,” says the husband. “I have a motorboat, but to tell you the truth we mostly use it to go to restaurants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether they’re entertaining the troops or enjoying their aerie alone, the owners never tire of gazing at the Severn, with the boats streaming by. “You get to know the people who are using the river and what it does in certain kinds of wind,” the homeowner reflects. “The river has a personality.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Renovation Architecture: Scott L. Rand, AIA, Annapolis, Maryland. Interior Design: Gina Fitzsimmons, ASID, Fitzsimmons Design Associates, Annapolis, Maryland. Landscape Design: Andrea Lockett, The Landscape Design Center, Edgewater, Maryland. Guest House Contractor: Patrick Mona, Mona Design Build, Annapolis, Maryland.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A couple revives a century-old compound perched above Maryland’s Severn Rive</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">REMODELLING A CLASSIC</title><link href="/2017/11/14/second-post-for-testing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="REMODELLING A CLASSIC" /><published>2017-11-14T19:52:15+02:00</published><updated>2017-11-14T19:52:15+02:00</updated><id>/2017/11/14/second-post-for-testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2017/11/14/second-post-for-testing.html">&lt;h2&gt;
REMODELLING A CLASSIC – JACKIE CHIESA WITH WILLIAM ASHLEY
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;
This new store boasts many improvements, which Jackie Chiesa hopes will make the customers’ shopping experience not only enjoyable, but also mesmerizing.
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Tillie Abrams opened the first William Ashley retail store 71 years ago, providing customers with top-quality products. Your own grandmother may have picked up her dinnerware set from there. And its popularity hasn’t waned over the years. Even today, ask any bride-to-be where she wants to register, and chances are she’ll say “William Ashley.”
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
At the helm of this operation is William Ashley’s president, Jackie Chiesa, who has been with the company for 36 years. “While I was in university, I took a part-time position at William Ashley, and I guess you can say I kind of worked my way up from the mailroom.” Mentored by Abrams herself, Chiesa says, “She would show me, ‘Jackie, this is quality tableware,’ and she would show me how the plate was decorated — true craftsmanship.” Chiesa can remember Abrams walking through the store, striking the edge of a plate to demonstrate the strength of bone china and its ability to absorb shock. This, among other things, displayed the true quality of their products to customers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
William Ashley has always been at the forefront of trends, fashion and design, offering customers the finest products and brands; from Daum to Wedgwood — the options are endless. It is also the exclusive Canadian distributor of the world-renowned Teuscher Chocolates of Switzerland. With dedication to its craft and carrying over 200 tableware, home décor and kitchen brands such as Baccarat, Lalique, Moser and Waterford, it is not surprising that William Ashley has maintained its spot as a premier destination in the retail world.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
April 27 marked a new milestone for this prolific company, opening its new flagship destination on Bloor Street West in Toronto. Set in a heritage building, it boasts 23-foot ceilings, natural light and impeccable architectural details, marking a new phase for this retail giant. It is “a phenomenal space in which to stage these iconic brands from all over the world,” says Chiesa.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Not only did Chiesa want to create a beautiful space, but she also wanted to enhance the experience of her customers by incorporating new features into this store. And technology has had a big part to play in the design. “Its impact on consumer behaviour has totally changed the world of retailing,” explains Chiesa. One aspect of the store that brings together technology and retail is the use of videos. “We have a 14-foot video wall that is filled with wonderful brand stories, telling you about their history.” On top of that, William Ashley is taking advantage of the data it has compiled over the years, “to understand our consumers and understand their history and exactly what that customer might be looking for today,” Chiesa says.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The retail landscape may currently be evolving, but William Ashley won’t be left behind. This new location has reached the peak of retail, creating a seamless and frictionless experience for its customers.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">REMODELLING A CLASSIC – JACKIE CHIESA WITH WILLIAM ASHLEY This new store boasts many improvements, which Jackie Chiesa hopes will make the customers’ shopping experience not only enjoyable, but also mesmerizing. Tillie Abrams opened the first William Ashley retail store 71 years ago, providing customers with top-quality products. Your own grandmother may have picked up her dinnerware set from there. And its popularity hasn’t waned over the years. Even today, ask any bride-to-be where she wants to register, and chances are she’ll say “William Ashley.” At the helm of this operation is William Ashley’s president, Jackie Chiesa, who has been with the company for 36 years. “While I was in university, I took a part-time position at William Ashley, and I guess you can say I kind of worked my way up from the mailroom.” Mentored by Abrams herself, Chiesa says, “She would show me, ‘Jackie, this is quality tableware,’ and she would show me how the plate was decorated — true craftsmanship.” Chiesa can remember Abrams walking through the store, striking the edge of a plate to demonstrate the strength of bone china and its ability to absorb shock. This, among other things, displayed the true quality of their products to customers. William Ashley has always been at the forefront of trends, fashion and design, offering customers the finest products and brands; from Daum to Wedgwood — the options are endless. It is also the exclusive Canadian distributor of the world-renowned Teuscher Chocolates of Switzerland. With dedication to its craft and carrying over 200 tableware, home décor and kitchen brands such as Baccarat, Lalique, Moser and Waterford, it is not surprising that William Ashley has maintained its spot as a premier destination in the retail world. April 27 marked a new milestone for this prolific company, opening its new flagship destination on Bloor Street West in Toronto. Set in a heritage building, it boasts 23-foot ceilings, natural light and impeccable architectural details, marking a new phase for this retail giant. It is “a phenomenal space in which to stage these iconic brands from all over the world,” says Chiesa. Not only did Chiesa want to create a beautiful space, but she also wanted to enhance the experience of her customers by incorporating new features into this store. And technology has had a big part to play in the design. “Its impact on consumer behaviour has totally changed the world of retailing,” explains Chiesa. One aspect of the store that brings together technology and retail is the use of videos. “We have a 14-foot video wall that is filled with wonderful brand stories, telling you about their history.” On top of that, William Ashley is taking advantage of the data it has compiled over the years, “to understand our consumers and understand their history and exactly what that customer might be looking for today,” Chiesa says. The retail landscape may currently be evolving, but William Ashley won’t be left behind. This new location has reached the peak of retail, creating a seamless and frictionless experience for its customers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Traditional Design</title><link href="/2017/09/13/first-post-for-testing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Traditional Design" /><published>2017-09-13T20:52:15+03:00</published><updated>2017-09-13T20:52:15+03:00</updated><id>/2017/09/13/first-post-for-testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2017/09/13/first-post-for-testing.html">&lt;h2&gt;Everything You Need To Know About Traditional Design&quot;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You might tend to shy away from traditional design out of fear that it's boring, predictable, stuffy—and it totally can be. But some of its facets are truly interesting, and since it incorporates a lot of antiques, traditional design gives the opportunity to stumble upon some pretty cool pieces. But what exactly makes something &quot;traditional&quot; and just how far back does traditional go? We'll tell you everything you need to know, and maybe you'll be convinced that traditional doesn't always equal staid.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
 Traditional Design Is Inspired By The 18th &amp;amp; 19th Centuries.
 &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As you would have probably surmised, traditional design is inspired by, well, tradition. It's a timeless style taking cues from the 18th and 19th centuries, incorporating classic art, antiques, and pieces with history. Though you'll most often see traditional design influenced by European decor, it can actually incorporate elements from England, France, or even the far east. &quot;Styles and pieces reflect historical design elements using natural materials and colors&quot; says interior designer Erin Gates.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
It Strives For Harmony And Order.
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
True, traditional designs orderly aesthetic can feel boring and staid, but it's predictable for a reason. Consistency is key, as traditional design seeks to create a calm, orderly space, so furnishings will match, symmetry is huge, and everything seems to just go together. Wild and chaotic do not jive with traditional design.
In the traditional design, you'll typically find neutral walls (it is predictable, after all), but color totally has a place. Art, textiles, and decor accents can help pop a room, and dark, rich jewel tones are most commonly used. Think red, brown, green, and plenty of dark wood. &quot;Palettes can be bold and saturated or pale and soft, but tend to be welcoming and not jarring or too graphic,&quot; Gates says.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
It's All In The Details.
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since order and consistency are essential, character comes in through details. Accessories are grand, like candle holders, vases, and chandeliers, and china, silver, and gold are commonly used. You'll find architectural details like crown molding, columns, and wood-paneling used through traditional design, which add a bit of opulence to a room without looking too ostentatious. Rooms are often centered around a focal point, like a fireplace or oil paintings.
You won't find blinds or bare window coverings in traditional homes. Drapery and valances are classic, usually with heavy curtains. Upholstery, whether for curtains, pillows, or furniture, tend to favor high-end fabrics like silk, velvet, and leather, and bold pattern comes in the form of damask, plaid, or paisley. Many fabrics go one step further with trim. &quot;On drapes, pillows, or upholstered goods—trim adds that little extra detail that shows that something was thoughtfully made&quot; Gates says.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Everything You Need To Know About Traditional Design&quot;</summary></entry></feed>